<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Hany Kashif</title>
		<description>Research Software Engineer</description>
		<link>//hkashif.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="//hkashif.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Building My First Home Server</title>
				<description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;older-home-setup&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Older Home Setup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, I had a couple of laptops at home, a WD NAS, and an Nvidia Shield TV box. I used the NAS mainly as a storage for photos, videos, music, and for the occasional backups from the laptops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Nvidia Shield, I used Kodi as a media center. I couldn’t simply stream videos to Kodi from the NAS .. huge performance issues. I had to buy a high-speed USB drive to extend the storage space on my 500 GB Shield to give more space for Kodi when using P2P downloads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What wasn’t I happy with?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frequent instabilities with Kodi on Shield.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Couldn’t stream videos directly from the NAS to Kodi.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To run a software overnight, I had to leave my laptop running.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laptop couldn’t leave home when I wanted to run a software uninterrupted over a period of time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Had no backup for the NAS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-did-i-need&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Did I Need?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was clear to me that I needed to upgrade things at home, so I started identifying what I wanted to have. Here is what I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better, more automated media setup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Proper backups of my data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to have software running for days collecting and churning data&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Private file hosting and sharing service&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to run multiple VMs (not on my laptop)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ability to securely access all of this remotely&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-are-my-options&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What Are My Options?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t really do an exhaustive analysis of what my options were. However, I considered a few options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extending my NAS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A more advanced NAS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Home workstation with some server OS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RAID server&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unRAID server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extending my NAS basically meant buying a similar one to what I currently have and connecting them for backups. This only solved one of my problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A more advanced NAS sounded like a good option at first. However, extending it for storage was not as simple. And I wasn’t sure I had any control over what I can run on that NAS. Maybe I would be able to run some apps but there will probably be a lot of limitations. The cost was not low either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A home workstation with a server OS was an appealing option. However, this meant no parity. I also was not sure about my options for monitoring the server. I am sure there are tools for that on the different server OSes, I, however, wanted to spend minimal effort for maintaining the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It ended up being a comparison between either a RAID server or an unRAID server. This is already a controversial topic. However, there were a few points that helped me make up mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unRAID does not stripe data across multiple disks. To me, this is safer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unRAID compensates for performance degradation due to not striping data via a cache drive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unRAID allows adding an asymmetric disk (with a size smaller than or equal to that of the parity drive)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unRAID does not spin all drives for reading and writing a file&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unRAID has a beautiful application store and has native docker support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unRAID has a strong community support forum&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unRAID does not need special hardware (compared to RAID)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unRAID OS has a one time cost which might be a deterrent for some. For me, however, the cost was completely justifiable specifically considering the cost involved in expanding my array in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-home-server&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Home Server&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was not the most exhaustive enumeration or analysis of my options, nevertheless, I decided to go with the unRAID OS. I made the following to-buy-hardware list for my server:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A used Dell PowerEdge T410
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;64GB ECC RAM&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;2 x Xeon X5670 12 Core CPUs&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;No RAID&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 x 4TB HGST 7200RPM 128M Cache NAS Drives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Samsung 970 EVO PLUS 512 GB SSD&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SSD NVMe PCIe Adapter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;USB Drive with a small form factor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The T410 came with a SAS backplane for the drives. The SAS backplane was powered by two 4-pin ATX connectors. The SAS backplane, however, didn’t have a connection to the motherboard. The reason is that I ordered the T410 with no RAID. A SAS backplane is connected to the motherboard through a RAID controller and cannot connect directly to the onboard SATA ports. I had two options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buy a H200 RAID controller and run the drives unconfigured (non RAID) to pass them through as individual drives.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get rid of the backplane and connect the drives directly to the motherboard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was not sure about the performance of the first option so I went with the second. I installed the cache drive into the SSD adapter and into a PCIe port in the motherboard. I setup the USB drive with the unRAID OS from an Ubunutu host as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Formatted the drive as FAT32&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unzipped the contents to the drive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edited the configuration files as needed (e.g., host name)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unmounted the USB drive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ran the ‘make bootable’ shell script from the local copy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is it. I put the USB drive into a port directly on the motherboard, closed the chassis, started the server, and it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In future posts, I will explain the software setup of the server.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 16:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>//hkashif.github.io/2019/09/unraid-hardware</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">//hkashif.github.io/2019/09/unraid-hardware</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>SQL Server Evaluation Expiry - Error 17051</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I had a SQL server instance up and running for a long period of time. The SQL server instance was installed with a valid product key. All of a sudden, none of my applications were able to connect to the server instance. I tried opening SQL Server Management Studio to check what’s going on. It threw the following error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A network-related or instance-specific error occurred while establishing a connection to SQL Server. The server was not found or was not accessible. Verify that the instance name is correct and that SQL Server is configured to allow remote connections. (provider: Named Pipes Provider, error: 40 - Could not open a connection to SQL Server) (Microsoft SQL Server, Error: 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I had no idea what this meant. However, I checked Windows services (&lt;strong&gt;services.msc&lt;/strong&gt;). Afterwards, I attempt restarting the SQL Server service, but it throws an error message saying that Windows cannot start the SQL server with an error code: &lt;strong&gt;17051&lt;/strong&gt;. Upon looking this up, it turns out that it means that the SQL Server evaluation period has expired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, I am 100% sure that I used a product key during installation, but this still sounds like an easy fix. I rerun the SQL Server installation file and attempt to upgrade my SQL Server. The installation process runs smoothly until it just fails when running the SQL engine health check (&lt;strong&gt;Engine__SqlEngineHealthCheck&lt;/strong&gt;). I bang my head against the wall trying to figure this one out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending too much time on this, it turns out that there is actually an option to skip the &lt;em&gt;SQL Engine Health Check&lt;/em&gt; for the upgrade to succeed. To use this opttion, however, the installation has to be triggered from a Command Line Prompt. To do this, use the upgrade parameters listed &lt;a href=&quot;https://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/ms144259.aspx#Upgrade&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and append to your parameters this option: &lt;strong&gt;/SkipRules= Engine__SqlEngineHealthCheck&lt;/strong&gt;. This fixed it all for me.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2017 12:36:06 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>//hkashif.github.io/2017/02/sqlserver-17051</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">//hkashif.github.io/2017/02/sqlserver-17051</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>My Signature Salad</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I spent a considerable amount of time trying a variety of salad recipes. I liked some of them, others not so much. Then, I started to play around with the components to make my own recipe, and find a salad that I truly enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A handful of baby spinach (minced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two to three thin cross-sections of iceberg lettuce (minced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One stack of celery (minced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One third of an English cucumber (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One half of a green bell pepper (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One half of a red/orange/yellow bell pepper (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two handfuls of cherry tomatoes (finely chopped)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One small avocado (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One half of a Gala apple (minced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A cup of crispy onions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use a variety of dressings with this salad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mixture of French dressing and balsamic vinaigrette&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zesty Italian dressing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My personal favorite; a whisked mix of olive oil, freshly squeezed lime juice, sumac, freshly ground black pepper, and an optional minced garlic clove&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 10:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>//hkashif.github.io/2016/07/signature-salad</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">//hkashif.github.io/2016/07/signature-salad</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Mirepoix</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A colleague of mine, recently, gave a presentation on the difference between taste and flavor. He also touched on vegetable mixtures that form the basis for a variety of dishes (including soups). For instance, the French &lt;em&gt;mirepoix&lt;/em&gt; is a mixture of onions, carrots, and celery. Throw in garlic, and you get the Italian &lt;em&gt;soffritto&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;holy trinity&lt;/em&gt;, for example, is a mixture of onions, celery, and bell peppers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This provoked me into trying to make a few soups that I like but never really cooked before. They all share the same base mirepoix mixture: a carrot, an onion, and a stalk of celery. Here are a few notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;butternut-squash-soup&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Butternut Squash Soup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mirepoix (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two medium potatoes (cubed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One medimum squash (cubed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chicken stock/broth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt the butter, and cook all vegetables till slightly browned&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour in stock/broth to cover the vegetables and bring to a boil, then simmer for 45 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a blender or a hand blender to to smoothen the soup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Season with salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;note warning&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wear a pair of gloves when cutting and cubing the squash. I haven’t found anything, so far, that successfully removes squash residue from hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;potato-chowder&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potato Chowder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mirepoix (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two medium potatoes (cubed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One and a half cups of chichen broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One cup of milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One cup of cooked chicken breast (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Half a cup of shredded cheddar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two tablespoons of all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A teaspoon of thyme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt the butter, and cook the mirepoix mix until slightly brown while adding in the thyme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in the flour, stir, add in the broth and the milk, stir till slightely thickened, add in the potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring to a boil, and simmer for 20 minutes, then add chicken and cheddar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir for a bit more, then season to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tomato-soup&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tomato Soup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mirepoix (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three large tomatoes on vines&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A can of plum tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three quarters a litre of chicken broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A tablespoon of garlic (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some basil leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt the butter, and cook the mirepoix mix until slightly brown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the broth, bring to a boil, then add in the fresh and plum tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring to a boil, then simmer for 20 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a hand blender to smoothen, and season to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;note info&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Leave the tomato vines in the mix, and remove before blending. They add a lot of flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;note warning&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you use a blender, make sure to start at the lowest speed. The size of the tomatoes can create pressure on the blender’s lid, spraying soup everywhere … not a pleasant experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 16:05:06 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>//hkashif.github.io/2016/07/mirepoix</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">//hkashif.github.io/2016/07/mirepoix</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
