<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Hany Kashif</title>
		<description>Research Software Engineer</description>
		<link>www.hanykashif.com</link>
		<atom:link href="www.hanykashif.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>My Signature Salad</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I spent a considerable amount of time trying a variety of salad recipes. I liked some of them, others not so much. Then, I started to play around with the components to make my own recipe, and find a salad that I truly enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A handful of baby spinach (minced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two to three thin cross-sections of iceberg lettuce (minced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One stack of celery (minced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One third of an English cucumber (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One half of a green bell pepper (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One half of a red/orange/yellow bell pepper (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two handfuls of cherry tomatoes (finely chopped)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One small avocado (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One half of a Gala apple (minced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A cup of crispy onions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use a variety of dressings with this salad:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mixture of French dressing and balsamic vinaigrette&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zesty Italian dressing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My personal favorite; a whisked mix of olive oil, freshly squeezed lime juice, sumac, freshly ground black pepper, and an optional minced garlic clove&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 10:02:00 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>www.hanykashif.com/2016/07/signature-salad</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">www.hanykashif.com/2016/07/signature-salad</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Mirepoix</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A colleague of mine, recently, gave a presentation on the difference between taste and flavor. He also touched on vegetable mixtures that form the basis for a variety of dishes (including soups). For instance, the French &lt;em&gt;mirepoix&lt;/em&gt; is a mixture of onions, carrots, and celery. Throw in garlic, and you get the Italian &lt;em&gt;soffritto&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;holy trinity&lt;/em&gt;, for example, is a mixture of onions, celery, and bell peppers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This provoked me into trying to make a few soups that I like but never really cooked before. They all share the same base mirepoix mixture: a carrot, an onion, and a stalk of celery. Here are a few notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;butternut-squash-soup&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Butternut Squash Soup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mirepoix (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two medium potatoes (cubed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One medimum squash (cubed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chicken stock/broth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt the butter, and cook all vegetables till slightly browned&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour in stock/broth to cover the vegetables and bring to a boil, then simmer for 45 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a blender or a hand blender to to smoothen the soup&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Season with salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;note warning&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wear a pair of gloves when cutting and cubing the squash. I haven’t found anything, so far, that successfully removes squash residue from hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;potato-chowder&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Potato Chowder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mirepoix (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two medium potatoes (cubed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One and a half cups of chichen broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One cup of milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One cup of cooked chicken breast (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Half a cup of shredded cheddar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two tablespoons of all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A teaspoon of thyme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt the butter, and cook the mirepoix mix until slightly brown while adding in the thyme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in the flour, stir, add in the broth and the milk, stir till slightely thickened, add in the potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring to a boil, and simmer for 20 minutes, then add chicken and cheddar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stir for a bit more, then season to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tomato-soup&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tomato Soup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mirepoix (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three large tomatoes on vines&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A can of plum tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three quarters a litre of chicken broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A tablespoon of garlic (diced)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some basil leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melt the butter, and cook the mirepoix mix until slightly brown&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the broth, bring to a boil, then add in the fresh and plum tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring to a boil, then simmer for 20 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a hand blender to smoothen, and season to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;note info&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Leave the tomato vines in the mix, and remove before blending. They add a lot of flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;note warning&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you use a blender, make sure to start at the lowest speed. The size of the tomatoes can create pressure on the blender’s lid, spraying soup everywhere … not a pleasant experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2016 16:05:06 -0400</pubDate>
				<link>www.hanykashif.com/2016/07/mirepoix</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">www.hanykashif.com/2016/07/mirepoix</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
